Guide to the Elliot Glass and Ken Marsh Video Collection MSS.334
Fales Library and Special Collections
Elliot Glass and Ken Marsh Video Collection
1970-1986
1970-1979
Fales Library and Special Collections
Glass, Elliot
Marsh, Ken, 1940-
MSS.334
34.6 Linear Feet in 23 record cartons, 4 cases, 1 box, and 2 objects
Elliot Glass and Ken Marsh are video producers and co-founders of the People's Video Theater. Marsh is the founder of Woodstock Community Video, Inc., and the Artists' TV Lab, and Glass is the founder of Crossroads Video. The Elliot Glass and Ken Marsh Video Collection contains video recordings created by the People's Video Theater, Woodstock Community Video, Inc., the Artists' TV Lab, and Crossroads Video, as well as video recording equipment used by those organizations, and individual art and written work created by Glass and Marsh. Material in the collection dates from 1970 to the mid-1980s, with the bulk of the material dating from 1970 to 1979.
Scope and Contents
The Elliot Glass and Ken Marsh Video Collection contains video recordings created by the People's Video Theater, Woodstock Community Video, Inc., the Artists' TV Lab, and Crossroads Video, as well as video recording equipment used by those organizations, and individual art and written work created by Glass and Marsh. Material in the collection dates from 1970 to the mid-1980s, with the bulk of the material dating from 1970 to 1979. The collection documents the work of Glass and Marsh as founders of the video journalism collective People's Video Theater (PVT), Marsh's work as founder of Woodstock Community Video, Inc. (WCV) and the Artists' TV Lab, and Glass's work as founder of Crossroads Video. Materials include master and production reel to reel video, videocassettes, and DVDs; Portapaks and accessories; newspaper and magazine clippings about PVT and WCV; grant applications; and books and articles related to the work of Glass and Marsh.
The material related to PVT includes roughly 50 original video recordings and 40 compilation recordings, grant applications, and clippings, dating from 1970 to 1971. The video recordings document the work of Glass and Marsh with the collective between 1970 and 1971, including the Women's Strike for Equality in New York, the first Gay Pride Parade, a Young Lords's protest occupation of a Manhattan church, and an action taken by Native Americans at Plymouth Rock on the 350th anniversary of the pilgrims's landing.
The material related to WCV includes roughly 250 master video recordings and 29 compilation video recordings, created between 1972 and 1979 by Marsh and other video artists in Woodstock, New York, including Gary Hill. Material from Artists' TV Lab consists of post-production video recordings left by artists in the studio between 1973 and 1978.
The collection also contains work created by Marsh and Glass apart from their collaborations. Marsh's works include multi-media and written works, including Weather Diary, a year long multimedia project, and two of his books on video production. Works by Glass include language and cultural videos produced by Crossroads Video, his language learning production and distribution company.
Biographical Note
Elliot Glass and Ken Marsh are video producers and co-founders of the People's Video Theater. Marsh is the founder of Woodstock Community Video, Inc., and the Artists' TV Lab, and Glass is the founder of Crossroads Video. The People's Video Theater (PVT) was founded in 1970 in New York City and Glass and Marsh were active in the organization between 1970 and 1971. Marsh moved to Woodstock, New York and founded Woodstock Community Video in 1972 and the Artists' TV Lab in 1973. Marsh was active in both organizations until 1979. After his work with PVT, Glass became a Spanish language educator and founded Crossroads Video, a language learning production and distribution company. He is also the author of a number of Spanish language textbooks.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Elliot Glass and Ken Marsh, 2011. The accession number associated with this gift is 2012.334.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials that have not been preserved may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact [repository name, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596] with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Access to some audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room.
Video recordings.; Video art -- United States.; Independent films -- Production and direction -- United States.; Protest movements -- United States.; People's Video Theater; Woodstock Community Video, Inc.; Artists' TV Lab; Crossroads Video (Firm)
- Indian Thanksgiving Part I, 1970-11; 334.0001 (Box 1, Reel 334.0001, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss334_0001)
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video, Duration: 30min., Reel Size: 5"
- Indian Thanksgiving Part II, 1970-11; 334.0002 (Box 1, Reel 334.0002, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss334_0002)
- Who We Are--Street Part I, 1971-05; 334.0003 (Box 1, Reel 334.0003)
- Who We Are--Street Part II, 1971-05; 334.0004 (Box 1, Reel 334.0004)
- Video Poll: Car Ban in NYC, 1970-06; 334.0005 (Box 1, Reel 334.0005)
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video, Duration: 20min., Reel Size: 4.5"
- Women's Lib '70 Street Real Hands, 1970; 334.0006 (Box 1, Reel 334.0006)
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video [Master], Duration: 20min., Reel Size: 4.5"
- Gay Lib 1970, 334.0007 (Box 1, Reel 334.0007)
- [untitled], undated; 334.0008 (Box 1, Reel 334.0008)
- LIBERATION '70, People's Video Theatre, 1970; 334.0009 (Box 1, Reel 334.0009)
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video, Duration: 25min., Reel Size: 5"
- New York to San Francisco Message, 1971; 334.0010 (Box 1, Reel 334.0010)
- Dem. Picnic Aug. 27 (1), undated; 334.0011 (Box 1, Reel 334.0011)
- Dem. Picnic, undated; 334.0012 (Box 1, Reel 334.0012)
- Stanchion Dance, 1973-11; 334.0013 (Box 1, Reel 334.0013)
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video, Duration: 20min., Reel Size: 5"
- [untitled], undated; 334.0014 (Box 1, Reel 334.0014)
- Six Sides of Harvey Fite 6, undated; 334.0015 (Box 1, Reel 334.0015)
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video [Master], Duration: 10min., Reel Size: 5"
- Six Sides of Harvey Fite 5, undated; 334.0016 (Box 1, Reel 334.0016)
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video [Master], Duration: 30min., Reel Size: 5"
- Six Sides of Harvey Fite 1, undated; 334.0017 (Box 1, Reel 334.0017)
- Nunicon Reel IV, undated; 334.0018 (Box 1, Reel 334.0018)
- Poetry at Bip's, 1978-05; 334.0019 (Box 1, Reel 334.0019)
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video [Master], Duration: 13min., Reel Size: 5"
- Meet the Family and Baby, 1974; 334.0020 (Box 1, Reel 334.0020)
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video, Duration: 26min., Reel Size: 5"
- Baby, 1975; 334.0021 (Box 1, Reel 334.0021)
- WCV Video Expovision '75 Intro, 1975; 334.0022 (Box 1, Reel 334.0022)
- Multi-County Comm. Dev. Corp., 1975; 334.0023 (Box 1, Reel 334.0023)
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video, Duration: 15min., Reel Size: 5"
- Woodstock Elections, 1971; 334.0024 (Box 1, Reel 334.0024)
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video [Original], Duration: 22min., Reel Size: 5"
- Weather-Spring, undated; 334.0025 (Box 1, Reel 334.0025)
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video [Copy], Duration: 30min., Reel Size: 5"
- Weather Rites '77, 1977; 334.0026 (Box 1, Reel 334.0026)
- Winberg I, undated; 334.0027 (Box 1, Reel 334.0027)
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video [Copy], Duration: 15min., Reel Size: 5"
- Leon Barrin + Lucille Blanch, 1976-05-13; 334.0028 (Box 1, Reel 334.0028)
- Dieter Froese_1971-75. B/W pieces, 334.0029 (Box 2, Reel 334.0029)
- Muppets w/Victor Borge, undated; 334.0030 (Box 2, Reel 334.0030)
- Eddie Micks II, 1975-06-09; 334.0031 (Box 2, Reel 334.0031)
- Lenox, undated; 334.0032 (Box 2, Reel 334.0032)
- Lenox RD Girls, undated; 334.0033 (Box 2, Reel 334.0033)
- [untitled], undated; 334.0034 (Box 2, Reel 334.0034)
- Make a screen; Make a scope, undated; 334.0035 (Box 2, Reel 334.0035)
- Barzin, 1976-05-13; 334.0036 (Box 2, Reel 334.0036)
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video, Duration: 23min., Reel Size: 5"
- [untitled], undated; 334.0037 (Box 2, Reel 334.0037)
- Basketball I, undated; 334.0038 (Box 2, Reel 334.0038)
- Lenox Girls, undated; 334.0039 (Box 2, Reel 334.0039)
- Weather-Summer, undated; 334.0040 (Box 2, Reel 334.0040)
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video [Copy], Duration: 20min., Reel Size: 5"
- Racoons. After coons synthesizer, undated; 334.0041 (Box 2, Reel 334.0041)
- Artistic TV Lab sampler, 1975; 334.0042 (Box 2, Reel 334.0042)
- Lenox Girls_slape, undated; 334.0043 (Box 2, Reel 334.0043)
- [untitled], undated; 334.0044 (Box 2, Reel 334.0044)
- Ken's Experiments, undated; 334.0045 (Box 2, Reel 334.0045)
- Reel III Proctor Bergman Act II TIV, undated; 334.0046 (Box 2, Reel 334.0046)
- TIV Reel IV Proctor Berg, undated; 334.0047 (Box 2, Reel 334.0047)
- Physical handicup, 1971; 334.0048 (Box 2, Reel 334.0048)
- Elderly feeding program, 1975; 334.0049 (Box 2, Reel 334.0049)
- Opus 40 Benefit, undated; 334.0050 (Box 2, Reel 334.0050)
- (Ken's Synthe I)?, undated; 334.0051 (Box 2, Reel 334.0051)
- Weather/Earth Base, undated; 334.0052 (Box 2, Reel 334.0052)
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video [Master], Duration: 14min., Reel Size: 5"
- Proctor Bergman Reel II, 1976-01-14; 334.0053 (Box 2, Reel 334.0053)
- Physical handi, 1971-05; 334.0054 (Box 2, Reel 334.0054)
- Corruptions, 1973; 334.0055 (Box 2, Reel 334.0055)
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video, Duration: 10min., Reel Size: 4.5"
- Interviews Lenox Rd, undated; 334.0056 (Box 2, Reel 334.0056)
- The Chivalric Novel, 1973-11; 334.0057 (Box 3, Reel 334.0057)
- Cada Quien Su Vida IV, undated; 334.0058 (Box 3, Reel 334.0058)
- Cada Quien Su Vida III, undated; 334.0059 (Box 3, Reel 334.0059)
- Cada Quien Su Vida II, undated; 334.0060 (Box 3, Reel 334.0060)
- Cada Quien Su Vida I, undated; 334.0061 (Box 3, Reel 334.0061)
- Nursing #1, undated; 334.0062 (Box 3, Reel 334.0062)
- Nurses 1, undated; 334.0063 (Box 3, Reel 334.0063)
- Nurses 2, undated; 334.0064 (Box 3, Reel 334.0064)
- [untitled], 1975-04; 334.0065 (Box 3, Reel 334.0065)
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video, Duration: 60min., Reel Size: 7"
- [untitled], undated; 334.0066 (Box 3, Reel 334.0066)
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video [Master], Duration: 60min., Reel Size: 7"
- Puerto Rican Indep.- La Marqueta, undated; 334.0067 (Box 3, Reel 334.0067)
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video [Dub], Duration: 60min., Reel Size: 7"
- Puerto Rican Independence, undated; 334.0068 (Box 3, Reel 334.0068)
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video [3rd generation copy], Duration: 60min., Reel Size: 7"
- [untitled], undated; 334.0069 (Box 3, Reel 334.0069)
- Edited Sephardic Material, 1977-05-22; 334.0070 (Box 3, Reel 334.0070)
- Baby '75, undated; 334.0071 (Box 3, Reel 334.0071)
- Verbos Ref. CV, undated; 334.0072 (Box 3, Reel 334.0072)
- PR./Cuban Dialects, undated; 334.0073 (Box 3, Reel 334.0073)
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video, Duration: 32min., Reel Size: 5"
- La Basura #1, undated; 334.0074 (Box 3, Reel 334.0074)
- Beth El #1, undated; 334.0075 (Box 3, Reel 334.0075)
- Hollywood pt. II, undated; 334.0076 (Box 3, Reel 334.0076)
- [untitled], undated; 334.0077 (Box 3, Cassette 334.0077)
  Format: S-VHS [Master]
- [untitled], 1973-12-21; 334.0078 (Box 3, Reel 334.0078)
- "Yo No" Medical Tape, undated; 334.0079 (Box 3, Reel 334.0079)
- Bratter House, undated; 334.0080 (Box 3, Reel 334.0080)
- WCV6- I, undated; 334.0081 (Box 4, Reel 334.0081)
- CV_, undated; 334.0082 (Box 4, Reel 334.0082)
- Live Forum at PVT-Cats in Catskills (cuts), 1970-06; 334.0083 (Box 4, Reel 334.0083)
- Video Magazine II, 1970-06; 334.0084 (Box 4, Reel 334.0084)
- August 26th Expovision Video Synthesizer Tape 1, undated; 334.0085 (Box 4, Reel 334.0085)
- Expovision Multi Media Event, undated; 334.0086 (Box 4, Reel 334.0086)
- 1968 Crisis Brooks (?) School, 334.0087 (Box 4, Reel 334.0087)
- Market Video Survey, 1970; 334.0088 (Box 4, Reel 334.0088)
- Willoughby Sharp, 1975; 334.0089 (Box 4, Reel 334.0089)
- WCV Video Expovision '75, 1975; 334.0090 (Box 4, Reel 334.0090)
- Artists TV Lab Sampler, 1976; 334.0091 (Box 4, Reel 334.0091)
- [untitled], undated; 334.0092 (Box 4, Reel 334.0092)
- [untitled], undated; 334.0093 (Box 4, Reel 334.0093)
- Woodstock Tonight Promo Loop, undated; 334.0094 (Box 4, Reel 334.0094)
- [untitled], undated; 334.0095 (Box 4, Reel 334.0095)
- Watergate '73, 1973; 334.0096 (Box 4, Reel 334.0096)
- Six Sides of Harvey Fite / Eddie Hicks, undated; cuid41539 (Box 5, Vhs 334.0097)
  Duration: 96 min.
- Woodstock Sampler / Woodstock Elections, undated; 334.0098 (Box 5, Cassette 334.0098)
  Format: VHS [Dub], Duration: 42min.
- Who We Are - Edit / Who We Are Pt II, undated; 334.0099 (Box 5, Cassette 334.0099)
  Format: U-matic [Master], Duration: 60min.
- Who We Are Pt 1, undated; 334.0100 (Box 5, Cassette 334.0100)
  Format: U-matic [Master], Duration: 30min.
- P.R. Independence / Washington D.C. Peace March / Car Ban Poll / Street Reel (Shoeshineman), undated; 334.0101 (Box 5, Cassette 334.0101)
  Format: U-matic [Dub], Duration: 31min.
- Who We Are - Edit / Who We Are Pt II, undated; 334.0102 (Box 5, Cassette 334.0102)
  Format: U-matic [Dub], Duration: 60min.
- Indian Thanksgiving Pt 1 and II, undated; 334.0103 (Box 5, Cassette 334.0103)
- NY to San Francisco Message / Writers Block, undated; 334.0104 (Box 5, Cassette 334.0104)
- Writers Block (cont), undated; 334.0105 (Box 5, Cassette 334.0105)
  Format: U-matic [Dub], Duration: 3min.
- Market Video Survey / Gay Liberation, 1970; 334.0106 (Box 5, Cassette 334.0106)
- Car Ban in Manhattan / Puerto Rican Independence Day / Video Experiment: "Old German Hippie" / Womens Lib Street Reel, 1970; 334.0107 (Box 5, Cassette 334.0107)
  Format: U-matic [Dub], Duration: 54min.
- Ken's Tape: 'PVT Copy", 1970; 334.0108 (Box 5, Cassette 334.0108)
  Format: U-matic [Dub], Duration: 45min.
- Who We Are Pt 1 / NY to San Francisco Message, undated; 334.0109 (Box 6, U-matic 334.0109)
  Duration: 56 min.
- N.Y. to S.F. Message, undated; 334.0112 (Box 6, U-matic 334.0112)
  Duration: 27 minutes
- 14th Street Survey: Gay Lib, undated; 334.0113 (Box 6, U-matic 334.0113)
  Duration: 56 minutes
- 14th Street Survey: Gay Lib, undated; 334.0114 (Box 6, U-matic 334.0114)
- CV #11, undated; 334.0115 (Box 6, Cassette 334.0115)
- Woodstock Sampler/Woodstock Elections, undated; 334.0116 (Box 6, Cassette 334.0116)
  Format: U-matic, Duration: 60min.
- [untitled], undated; 334.0117 (Box 6, Cassette 334.0117)
- N.Y. to S.F. Message -or- Indian Thanksgiving Pts. 1 + 2, undated; 334.0119 (Box 7, Cassette 334.0119)
- Weather Rites 1977: Earth Scenes and Satellite Shots, 334.0120 (Box 7, Cassette 334.0120)
  Format: U-matic, Duration: 20min.
- Weather Rites 1977: Earth Base and Satellite Base, undated; 334.0121 (Box 7, Cassette 334.0121)
  Format: U-matic, Duration: 30min.
- Fite / Woodstock / NYC Street / Eddie Hicks, undated; 334.0122 (Box 7, Cassette 334.0122)
- PVT 1970 Gay Lib March and Events, 334.0123 (Box 7, S-vhs 334.0123)
  Duration: 16 minutes
- PVT Retro, undated; 334.0124 (Box 7, S-vhs 334.0124)
  Duration: 84 minutes
- PVT Demo, undated; 334.0125 (Box 7, Vhs 334.0125)
  Duration: 27 min.
- Liberation Tape 1970 / Young Lords - Roldan in Church, 334.0126 (Box 7, Vhs 334.0126)
  Duration: 31 minutes
- Mind Matters, Inc, 1991; 334.0127 (Box 7, Cassette 334.0127)
  Format: VHS, Duration: 60min.
- PVT 001, undated; 334.0128 (Box 7, Vhs 334.0128)
  Duration: 96 minutes
- PVT 002, undated; 334.0129 (Box 7, Vhs 334.0129)
  Duration: 66 minutes
- PVT 003, undated; 334.0130 (Box 7, Cassette 334.0130)
  Format: VHS, Duration: 120min.
- PVT 003 Dub, undated; 334.0131 (Box 7, Cassette 334.0131)
  Format: VHS [Dub], Duration: 120min.
- PVT 004, undated; 334.0132 (Box 7, Cassette 334.0132)
  Format: VHS, Duration: 90min.
- PVT 004 Dub, undated; 334.0133 (Box 7, Cassette 334.0133)
- Tapes 1 and 2, undated; 334.0134 (Box 7, Cassette 334.0134)
- Tapes 1 and 2, undated; 334.0135 (Box 7, Cassette 334.0135)
- Tapes 3 and 4, undated; 334.0136 (Box 7, Cassette 334.0136)
- Tapes 3 and 4, undated; 334.0137 (Box 7, Cassette 334.0137)
- Tapes 5 and 6, undated; 334.0138 (Box 7, Cassette 334.0138)
- Tapes 7 and 8, undated; 334.0139 (Box 7, Cassette 334.0139)
- Tapes 7 and 8, undated; 334.0140 (Box 7, Cassette 334.0140)
- Window Dubs 3/4" Masters #12 + # 1 1) Indian Thanksgiving Pt. 1 and 2, 2) Who We Are Edit/ Who We Are pt 2, undated; 334.0141 (Box 7, Cassette 334.0141)
  Format: VHS [Dub], Duration: 104min.
- Window Dub 3 1) NY to San Francisco Message 2) Writers Block, undated; 334.0142 (Box 7, Cassette 334.0142)
  Format: VHS [Dub], Duration: 60min.
- Window Dub CV #10 + #11 10 ) Market Video Survey; gay liberation 11) video poll-cerban; puerto rican indeo. day; 'video experiment'; womens Liberation, street reel, undated; 334.0143 (Box 7, Cassette 334.0143)
- Ken's Tape / Who We Are Pt 1 / NY to San Francisco Message, undated; 334.0144 (Box 7, Cassette 334.0144)
- Pavarotti, Horne and Sutherland 3/81 Concert from Lincoln Ctr III, undated; 334.0145 (Box 8, Reel 334.0145)
- Pavarotti, Horne and Sutherland II (3/81) Concert from Lincoln Ctr, undated; 334.0146 (Box 8, Reel 334.0146)
- Natl Geographic The Invisible World, undated; 334.0147 (Box 8, Reel 334.0147)
- Key to the Universe (off-air) May 30, 1977 2hours Color 2, 334.0148 (Box 8, Reel 334.0148)
- [untitled], undated; 334.0149 (Box 8, Reel 334.0149)
- [untitled], undated; 334.0150 (Box 8, Reel 334.0150)
- Amazon Media - "Looking for the Amazons" - Norma Bahia and Rita Moreira, undated; 334.0151 (Box 8, Reel 334.0151)
- Synergism Wat I Oct. 3, undated; 334.0152 (Box 8, Reel 334.0152)
- Artists' TV Lab RD 1 Box 2C Rhinebeck, NY 12572 914-876-3597 Sampler I master edit high density, undated; 334.0153 (Box 8, Reel 334.0153)
- Raster Video by Hansa/Scott, undated; 334.0154 (Box 8, Reel 334.0154)
- CV PVT Video Magazine I June 1970, 334.0155 (Box 8, Reel 334.0155)
- Long Live Life 324 Stockholm Environment Earth: Voice April Video Coop Downsville N.Y. 13755, undated; 334.0156 (Box 8, Reel 334.0156)
- Music Art Show Tape PS 126 J. Lipfield, undated; 334.0157 (Box 8, Reel 334.0157)
- Muppets otter X-Mas, Artists TV Lab Rhinebeck NY 12572 914-876-3597, undated; 334.0158 (Box 8, Reel 334.0158)
- WAA Showtape?, 1975; 334.0159 (Box 8, Reel 334.0159)
- West Hurley Elem. School Report, 1974; 334.0160 (Box 9, Reel 334.0160)
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video [Edit Copy], Duration: 13min., Reel Size: 4.5"
- Weather Fall, undated; 334.0161 (Box 9, Reel 334.0161)
- [untitled], undated; 334.0162 (Box 9, Reel 334.0162)
- Dodge II, undated; 334.0163 (Box 9, Reel 334.0163)
- WOODSTOCK MUSIC CO-OP, undated; 334.0164 (Box 9, Reel 334.0164)
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video [Unedited], Duration: 15min., Reel Size: 5"
- Getting Back, undated; 334.0165 (Box 9, Reel 334.0165)
- IMPROVISE A FEATURE MOVIE ON VIDEOTAPE, undated; 334.0166 (Box 9, Reel 334.0166)
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video, Duration: 10min., Reel Size: 5"
- Opus 40 w/ Sara Cook I of II, 1975-10-21; 334.0167 (Box 9, Reel 334.0167)
- Winberg I, undated; 334.0168 (Box 9, Reel 334.0168)
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video [Master Edit], Duration: 15min., Reel Size: 5"
- MESSAGE TO SAN FRANCISCO, 1971; 334.0169 (Box 9, Reel 334.0169)
- TRANSFORMATION OF POWER, 1974; 334.0170 (Box 9, Reel 334.0170)
- Cattle Sale, 1973-04-07; 334.0171 (Box 9, Reel 334.0171)
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video [Edit master], Duration: 26min., Reel Size: 5"
- Ken's Experiments, undated; 334.0172 (Box 9, Reel 334.0172)
- Proctor+Bergman Reel III NUVICON, undated; 334.0173 (Box 9, Reel 334.0173)
- Magic Markle 28th Day, undated; 334.0174 (Box 9, Reel 334.0174)
- Pretty much as jails, 1971-12; 334.0175 (Box 9, Reel 334.0175)
- Video Gallery #3, 1976; 334.0176 (Box 10, Reel 334.0176)
- Video Experiment: strip movie clip., undated; 334.0177 (Box 10, Reel 334.0177)
- PR Indenpendence, 1970; 334.0178 (Box 10, Reel 334.0178)
- Who We Are, 1971-05; 334.0179 (Box 10, Reel 334.0179)
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video [Edit], Duration: 13min., Reel Size: 5"
- New York To San Francisco Mess., undated; 334.0180 (Box 10, Reel 334.0180)
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video [Edit], Duration: 25min., Reel Size: 5"
- video magazine-Boston Gap, undated; 334.0181 (Box 10, Reel 334.0181)
- SIX SIDES OF HARVEY FITE 3,The Woodstock Art Colony, undated; 334.0182 (Box 10, Reel 334.0182)
- Gun Poll, undated; 334.0183 (Box 10, Reel 334.0183)
- Writers' block, undated; 334.0184 (Box 10, Reel 334.0184)
- David Frost Show Vision Takeover, undated; 334.0185 (Box 10, Reel 334.0185)
- Ken Marsh, undated; 334.0186 (Box 10, Reel 334.0186)
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video, Duration: 3min., Reel Size: 5"
- Video Experiment: Song Over Visuals-Old German Hippie, undated; 334.0187 (Box 10, Reel 334.0187)
- Base IV, 1975-08-07; 334.0188 (Box 10, Reel 334.0188)
- Ken Marsh's Birthday Party, 1974; 334.0189 (Box 10, Reel 334.0189)
- [untitled], undated; 334.0190 (Box 10, Reel 334.0190)
- WCV meeting I-feedbackI, undated; 334.0191 (Box 10, Reel 334.0191)
- Metrovision, undated; 334.0192 (Box 10, Reel 334.0192)
- Dem.Picnic, undated; 334.0193 (Box 10, Reel 334.0193)
- [untitled], undated; 334.0194 (Box 10, Reel 334.0194)
- Computer Art, 1975; 334.0195 (Box 10, Reel 334.0195)
- [untitled], undated; 334.0196 (Box 10, Reel 334.0196)
- Catskill Game Farm I, 1972; 334.0197 (Box 10, Reel 334.0197)
- SIX SIDES OF HARVEY FITE 4, A Quarrymans Museum, undated; 334.0198 (Box 11, Reel 334.0198)
- Meet The Family;Watergate with P.S., 1974; 334.0199 (Box 11, Reel 334.0199)
- Jon Berg- Studies I, undated; 334.0200 (Box 11, Reel 334.0200)
- Weather-Summer, undated; 334.0201 (Box 11, Reel 334.0201)
- Tom Beshaw Oct 12, 78 ATT, I, 1978-10-12; 334.0202 (Box 11, Reel 334.0202)
- Tad and John Richards, undated; 334.0203 (Box 11, Reel 334.0203)
- 1971- Woodstock-Video Introduction/Training, 334.0204 (Box 11, Reel 334.0204)
- Video Culture, undated; 334.0205 (Box 11, Reel 334.0205)
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video, Duration: 13min., Reel Size: 5"
- Six Side of Harvey Fite, undated; 334.0206 (Box 11, Reel 334.0206)
- Jon Berg- studio II, undated; 334.0207 (Box 11, Reel 334.0207)
- [untitled], undated; 334.0208 (Box 11, Reel 334.0208)
- GIVING BIRTH, 1971; 334.0209 (Box 11, Reel 334.0209)
- Onteora Students at Kingston Hospitals, 1974-11-11; 334.0210 (Box 11, Reel 334.0210)
- #2 Leon Barzin + Lucille Blanch, 1976-05-13; 334.0211 (Box 11, Reel 334.0211)
- Lenox Rd. Girls, undated; 334.0212 (Box 11, Reel 334.0212)
- Associate Artists Program, 1978-05; 334.0213 (Box 11, Reel 334.0213)
- Vasulkas I, undated; 334.0214 (Box 11, Reel 334.0214)
- FITE-OPUS 40, II of II, 1975-10-12; 334.0215 (Box 11, Reel 334.0215)
- [untitled], undated; 334.0216 (Box 11, Reel 334.0216)
- WCV History- Edit Sketch, 1976-07; 334.0217 (Box 11, Reel 334.0217)
- Eddie Hicks IV, 1976-06-09; 334.0218 (Box 11, Reel 334.0218)
- Meet the Family, 1974; 334.0219 (Box 11, Reel 334.0219)
  Format: 1/2 Open Reel Video [Edit Copy], Duration: 10min., Reel Size: 4.5"
- SIX SIDES OF HARVEY FITE 2, undated; 334.0220 (Box 11, Reel 334.0220)
- Southern Craftsmen I, 1973; 334.0221 (Box 12, Reel 334.0221)
- [untitled], undated; 334.0222 (Box 12, Reel 334.0222)